<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Geopop on Antonino Sirchia</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/tags/geopop/</link><description>Recent content in Geopop on Antonino Sirchia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://antoninosirchia.it/en/tags/geopop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is Computer RAM and What Are Its Functions</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/ram-geopop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/ram-geopop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine breathing life into the beating heart of your computer: RAM, or random access memory, is what allows every application to operate smoothly and responsively. In this article, originally published on Geopop, I explore in detail the essential role of this component, unveiling its technical secrets and illustrating how the various types of RAM can influence your system&amp;rsquo;s everyday performance. Through practical examples and in-depth insights, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover why every byte counts and how to optimize your computing environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The History of Robotics: From Early Inventions to the Frontiers of Artificial Intelligence</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/robotics-geopop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jul 2023 10:14:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/robotics-geopop/</guid><description>&lt;p>A fascinating journey through time, where human ingenuity transformed simple machines into sophisticated intelligent systems.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In this article that I wrote for Geopop, I retrace the fundamental milestones of robotics, from the earliest mechanical inventions to the modern applications that intertwine robotics and artificial intelligence. With historical anecdotes, critical analysis, and reflections on the future, this piece will offer you a comprehensive overview of an ever-evolving field, highlighting its ethical and social implications.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>