<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Antonino Sirchia</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/</link><description>Recent content on Antonino Sirchia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://antoninosirchia.it/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Liquid Computing at GDG Palermo - January 2025</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/gdg-palermo-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/gdg-palermo-25/</guid><description>&lt;div class="row">
&lt;div class="col col-sm-12 col-lg-6">
&lt;p>When &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://marcomartorana.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marco Martorana&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> asked me to speak at GDG Palermo on a topic of my choice, I had a moment of hesitation. I wanted to choose a subject that was not only interesting for the audience but also something I was truly passionate about. After some reflection, I decided to talk about &lt;strong>Liquid Computing&lt;/strong>, a concept I had recently explored in-depth for some articles published on &lt;strong>TheRedCode&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read my articles on this topic here: &lt;a href="https://theredcode.it/architetture/intro-liquid-computing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Liquid Computing: Optimization and Fluidity for Kubernetes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is Computer RAM and What Are Its Functions</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/ram-geopop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Aug 2023 23:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/ram-geopop/</guid><description>&lt;p>Imagine breathing life into the beating heart of your computer: RAM, or random access memory, is what allows every application to operate smoothly and responsively. In this article, originally published on Geopop, I explore in detail the essential role of this component, unveiling its technical secrets and illustrating how the various types of RAM can influence your system&amp;rsquo;s everyday performance. Through practical examples and in-depth insights, you&amp;rsquo;ll discover why every byte counts and how to optimize your computing environment.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Generative AI: A Technological Revolution in Progress</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/gen-ai/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2023 14:30:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/gen-ai/</guid><description>&lt;p>Generative AI is rapidly emerging as one of the most fascinating and promising technologies of our time. But what exactly is it, and how does it work? In simple terms, it is a form of artificial intelligence capable of creating new and original content using machine learning algorithms.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The generated content can span various fields, including music, art, design, and even writing. In this article, we will explore how Generative AI is being used today, its potential impact on the job market and industry, and discuss the implications of this emerging technology.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>How I'm Using My IT Skills Against the Covid-19 Pandemic</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/covid-19/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2020 17:12:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/covid-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>The Covid-19 emergency has tested not only healthcare systems but also the responsiveness of technology and people. Today, I want to share how my team and I, through our IT skills, contributed to supporting the Italian healthcare system, helping to save lives.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="the-beginning-of-a-global-challenge">The Beginning of a Global Challenge&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>It was February 28, 2020. Returning from a vacation day, I received a call from my boss. He looked at me and, with a serious tone, said:&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>