<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Conferences on Antonino Sirchia</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/tags/conferences/</link><description>Recent content in Conferences on Antonino Sirchia</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:41:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://antoninosirchia.it/en/tags/conferences/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Liquid Computing at GDG Palermo - January 2025</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/gdg-palermo-25/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 20:41:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/gdg-palermo-25/</guid><description>&lt;div class="row">
&lt;div class="col col-sm-12 col-lg-6">
&lt;p>When &lt;strong>&lt;a href="https://marcomartorana.it/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Marco Martorana&lt;/a>&lt;/strong> asked me to speak at GDG Palermo on a topic of my choice, I had a moment of hesitation. I wanted to choose a subject that was not only interesting for the audience but also something I was truly passionate about. After some reflection, I decided to talk about &lt;strong>Liquid Computing&lt;/strong>, a concept I had recently explored in-depth for some articles published on &lt;strong>TheRedCode&lt;/strong>.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>You can read my articles on this topic here: &lt;a href="https://theredcode.it/architetture/intro-liquid-computing/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Liquid Computing: Optimization and Fluidity for Kubernetes&lt;/a>.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My FIWARE Global Summit in the Canary Islands</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/fiware-summit-22/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/fiware-summit-22/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recently, I had the privilege of attending the 8th &lt;strong>FIWARE Global Summit&lt;/strong> in Las Palmas de Gran Canaria, an international event that brought together over 400 participants, 150 speakers, and hundreds of presentations, offering a total immersion in the FIWARE ecosystem and its countless applications in smart cities, agri-food, energy, and more.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>In the days leading up to the event, expectations were sky-high. As is typical when approaching conferences of this caliber, the desire to catch up on the latest cutting-edge innovations, engage with international experts, and discover new technological solutions was palpable. There was a strong anticipation to immerse oneself in a stimulating environment, where every presentation could be a key piece in understanding how digital technology is transforming urban infrastructures and beyond.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My FIWARE Global Summit in Genoa</title><link>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/fiware-summit-19/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 May 2019 19:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://antoninosirchia.it/en/posts/fiware-summit-19/</guid><description>&lt;p>Participating in the &lt;strong>FIWARE Summit 2019&lt;/strong> was an unforgettable experience—a journey that managed to combine the modernity of open source technologies with the historical richness of a unique city like Genoa. Set against the evocative backdrop of Genoa’s &lt;strong>Porto Antico&lt;/strong>, inside the ancient warehouses that once powered the port economy, the Summit provided the perfect stage to explore the new frontiers of digital transformation and to forge connections that went far beyond the mere exchange of ideas.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>